<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Package on Stop this train</title>
    <link>https://christineeeeee.com/tags/package/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Package on Stop this train</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 10 May 2020 09:20:58 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://christineeeeee.com/tags/package/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Flair - A Pretrained NLP Sentiment Analysis Tool</title>
      <link>https://christineeeeee.com/posts/nlp_sentiment_tool/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 May 2020 09:20:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://christineeeeee.com/posts/nlp_sentiment_tool/</guid>
      <description>NLP(Natural Language Processing) includes sentiment analysis. Trained sentiment analysis includes machine learning, which is of course more accurate. For beginners who just stepped into this field, getting to know some pretrained sentiment analysis tools may also be a good choice. Here, I want to introduce a package I used to analyze sentiment. It&amp;rsquo;s called flair.
Flair&amp;rsquo;s mechanism is simple. It contains a powerful library which allows users to use and combine different word and document embeddings.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Twint - A Twitter Scaping Tool</title>
      <link>https://christineeeeee.com/posts/twint/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 May 2020 17:16:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://christineeeeee.com/posts/twint/</guid>
      <description>Recently I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on a python project about a twitter sentiment trading strategy(which will be introduced in my following posts), which requires a large load of tweets. While collecting data on Twitter, I found out that usual data crawling doesn&amp;rsquo;t work here since there&amp;rsquo;s limitation of Twitter&amp;rsquo;s API which only allows us to scrap at most last 3200 Tweets. This post introduces a really interesting and useful python package I found out which could be used to collect data without authentication, API and limitations.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>