<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Math on Christine&#39;s Shattered Life</title>
    <link>https://christineeeeee.com/tags/math/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Math on Christine&#39;s Shattered Life</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 02 Aug 2020 22:36:15 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://christineeeeee.com/tags/math/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Martingale Approach to Achieve Certain Occurrence of Sequence Patterns</title>
      <link>https://christineeeeee.com/posts/martingale_coin_toss/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Aug 2020 22:36:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://christineeeeee.com/posts/martingale_coin_toss/</guid>
      <description>A classic probability problem: repeatedly toss a coin until consecutive pattern HTHT shows up, what&amp;rsquo;s the expected number of tosses?
 The normal solution to this problem is to use markov chains to calculate the expected time of the pattern to show up. However, there&amp;rsquo;s another more efficient way. This way was first came out in 1980 by Shuo-Yen Robert Li in his paper A Martigale Approach to the Study of Occurrence of Sequence Patterns in Repeated Experiments.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Monty Hall Problem</title>
      <link>https://christineeeeee.com/posts/monty_hall/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jul 2020 13:56:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://christineeeeee.com/posts/monty_hall/</guid>
      <description>Monty Hall Problem is a classic probability puzzle based on an American show called $Let&amp;rsquo;s \ Make \ a \ Deal$. While it brings joy to the audience, it also keeps torturing math students and people wanted to have a future in this field (just kidding). In this post, I summarized the classic Monty Hall Problem and some of its variants.
Classic Monty Hall Problem Let&amp;rsquo;s assume you&amp;rsquo;re the participant of the show and you&amp;rsquo;re standing before 3 doors which look exactly like the others.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Catch the Princess if You Can</title>
      <link>https://christineeeeee.com/posts/princess_behind_door/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jun 2020 10:25:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://christineeeeee.com/posts/princess_behind_door/</guid>
      <description>There&amp;rsquo;s a prince who&amp;rsquo;s madly in love with a lovely princess who lives in a tremendously big castle where there&amp;rsquo;re 7 bedrooms. Each bedroom in the castle has doors connecting tothe adjoining bedrooms. The princess sleeps in a different bedroom every night by opening the door to an adjoining bedroom. There&amp;rsquo;s no restriction on the direction of princess&amp;rsquo;s movement. As long as she sleeps in different bedrooms every night, she&amp;rsquo;s good.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes on Stochastic Calculus</title>
      <link>https://christineeeeee.com/posts/notes_stocal/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Feb 2020 21:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://christineeeeee.com/posts/notes_stocal/</guid>
      <description>Here I put some notes on the stochastic calculus for my future use. Those are some important (but also basic) properties and proofs about topics like moment generating function, martigales and Brownian motion etc. that we should know.
MGF of Normal Distribution For $X \sim N(\mu, \sigma^2)$, we have MGF($\theta$) = exp($\theta\mu + \theta^2\sigma^2 / 2)$. We have E($X^k$) = $MGF^{(k)}(0)$.
Truncated Normal Distribution A two-sided truncation $(a, b)$ on $N(\mu, \sigma^2)$, then: $$E[X | a &amp;lt; X &amp;lt; b] = \mu - \sigma \frac{\phi(\alpha) - \phi(\beta)}{\Phi(\alpha) - \Phi(\beta)}$$ where $\alpha: (a - \mu) / \sigma $ and $\beta: (b - \mu)/\sigma$</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Numerical Methods(1) - Binomial Model</title>
      <link>https://christineeeeee.com/posts/binomial_model/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2020 14:03:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://christineeeeee.com/posts/binomial_model/</guid>
      <description>This &amp;ldquo;Numerical Methods&amp;rdquo; series will be my notes on different kinds of useful numerical methods that are still frequently used in the industry. Binomial tree model will be the first one to be introduced.
Introduction To build a basic binomial tree, instead of building an N-period model, just let N=3. So the following&amp;rsquo;s a 3-period model with a bank account $B_t = e^{rt}$ and a stock $S$ with dynamics. About the notation of this model, the superscript represents the stock price and the subscript $t_n = n\Delta t$ for $n = 0, 1,&amp;hellip;,N$.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes on Probability and Distribution</title>
      <link>https://christineeeeee.com/posts/notes_prob/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2019 12:02:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://christineeeeee.com/posts/notes_prob/</guid>
      <description>Here, I take some notes on probability and distribution for the convenience of my future reference.
Dicrete Random Variables 1. Uniform Distribution  pmf: $P(x) = \frac{1}{b-a+1}$ for x = a, a + 1,&amp;hellip;,b E[$X$]: $\frac{a+b}{2}$ var($X$): $\frac{(b-a+1)^2 - 1}{12}$ meaning: it represents the occurrence of a value between number $a$ and $b$ when all values in the set {a, a+1,&amp;hellip;,b} have equal probability.  2. Binomial Distribution  pmf: $P(x) = {n \choose x} p^{x} (1-p)^{n-x}$ for x = 0, 1,&amp;hellip;,n E[$X$]: $np$ var($X$): $np(1-p)$ meaning: it represents the number of successes in a sequence of $n$ experiments when each trial is independently a success with probability $p$.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>