<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Strategy on Stop this train</title>
    <link>https://christineeeeee.com/tags/strategy/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Strategy on Stop this train</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 05 Jun 2020 18:08:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://christineeeeee.com/tags/strategy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Twitter Sentiment Strategy</title>
      <link>https://christineeeeee.com/posts/twitter_sentiment/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jun 2020 18:08:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://christineeeeee.com/posts/twitter_sentiment/</guid>
      <description>1. Introduction This is an exploratory research trying to implement a sentiment analysis mechanism of ten of the most discussed techonology stocks in the market nowadays. By collecting people&amp;rsquo;s discussions about the stocks on twitter, we used NLP (Natural language processing) to analyze people&amp;rsquo;s reactions and guesses of the market and got a score which indicates people&amp;rsquo;s positive or negative attitudes towards those certain stocks. Based on the daily scores we get, we adjusted our positions automatically.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Robust and Bayesian Regression Comparison</title>
      <link>https://christineeeeee.com/posts/robust_comparison/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 May 2020 02:08:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://christineeeeee.com/posts/robust_comparison/</guid>
      <description>Robust techniques and variable selection can help us obtain more stable linear fits. In this post, I used return regressions against returns on State Street sctors ETFs to test this fact. By computing out-of-sample regression, I contrast the performance of OLS regression, robust regression(huber and tukey) and positive lasso regressions.
1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12  import os import quandl import pickle import warnings import numpy as np import pandas as pd import seaborn as sns from tqdm.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Return predictions From Trade Flow</title>
      <link>https://christineeeeee.com/posts/trade_flow/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Apr 2020 13:24:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://christineeeeee.com/posts/trade_flow/</guid>
      <description>This is a strategy which is based on tick level analysis. The idea is that we use trade flow as our signals of the market to generate profit opportunities.
We define j as our trading threshold. Also, we need to decide proper $\tau$ as the backward trade interval and T as the forward trade interval.
1. Introduction Breif intro of the strategy.
Order Book and Trade Marking In the order book, there&amp;rsquo;re two types of trades: bid and ask.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spread Trading Strategy</title>
      <link>https://christineeeeee.com/posts/spread_trading/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Mar 2020 22:16:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://christineeeeee.com/posts/spread_trading/</guid>
      <description>This is a spreading strategy which is based on M-day returns of two highly related futures. The idea of this strategy is to hedge the risk of buying and holding one specific future with increasing returns by holding the opposite position of another future.
We define g and j be our trading thresholds in this strategy. Besides, we also have stop-loss threshold s. Our initial capital K is $100MM.
1. Introduction In this section we give brief intro on the strategy we&amp;rsquo;re about to implement.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>