<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Stop this train</title>
    <link>https://christineeeeee.com/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Stop this train</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 Jul 2020 14:46:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://christineeeeee.com/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>远方传来故人的消息</title>
      <link>https://christineeeeee.com/posts/far_away/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jul 2020 14:46:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://christineeeeee.com/posts/far_away/</guid>
      <description>早晨无意间听闻E君的好消息，坐在床上发愣了蛮久，男朋友唤了我几遍才缓过神来，穿好衣服坐到餐桌前吃饭，边吃饭还是边在回味这则消息，一时间不知道该说些什么。吃完饭做了一会儿正经事，跟闺蜜感慨，这个世界上能让我真正为其好消息而感到快乐甚至祝福的人，真的是少之又少了，而E君一定算一个。这条路这样难走，又这样长，换作是我，甚至不知道该如何走下去，可他还是这样坚决地走完了，有了这样不错的结局。就这样跟闺蜜聊到一半，我甚至又一次哽咽，跑到厕所坐在马桶上哭了一会儿，才平静了下来。
我们走了这么长的路，彼此相伴，最终还是在分叉路口彼此渐行渐远。最近看heart signal 3，有时候会想，如果命运真的这样捉弄人，那我们是不是真的只需要服从上天的安排就够了，努力的意义到底是什么。深夜的时候，我经常想起倒数第几通电话时，E君曾跟我讲觉得那么长的时间都白过了。这句话像一根刺，狠狠地扎进了我的心里，直到如今想起来，还是觉得隐隐作痛。今天的消息让我终于明白，并坚定地觉得，曾经彼此结伴的意义或许并不是为了一起走到地老天荒，更重要的是，我们在时间的流逝中，如同流水一般在彼此身上镌刻下了永远无法被磨灭的痕迹，哪怕不能互相陪伴，也分别在各自的路上继续走着，看着更美好的风景。
我不知道能不能等来对方真心为我祝福的一天，可我却一如既往地，从对方身上获得了力量。那样难的路，总可以走得完，我想我也可以继续在我的路上前行了。或许对方永远也不会知道这一些，这些其实也并不重要，但只需要我自己明白，我永远是这个世界上，能献上最真心祝愿的那一群人之一。</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Twitter Sentiment Strategy</title>
      <link>https://christineeeeee.com/posts/twitter_sentiment/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jun 2020 18:08:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://christineeeeee.com/posts/twitter_sentiment/</guid>
      <description>1. Introduction This is an exploratory research trying to implement a sentiment analysis mechanism of ten of the most discussed techonology stocks in the market nowadays. By collecting people&amp;rsquo;s discussions about the stocks on twitter, we used NLP (Natural language processing) to analyze people&amp;rsquo;s reactions and guesses of the market and got a score which indicates people&amp;rsquo;s positive or negative attitudes towards those certain stocks. Based on the daily scores we get, we adjusted our positions automatically.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Robust and Bayesian Regression Comparison</title>
      <link>https://christineeeeee.com/posts/robust_comparison/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 May 2020 02:08:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://christineeeeee.com/posts/robust_comparison/</guid>
      <description>Robust techniques and variable selection can help us obtain more stable linear fits. In this post, I used return regressions against returns on State Street sctors ETFs to test this fact. By computing out-of-sample regression, I contrast the performance of OLS regression, robust regression(huber and tukey) and positive lasso regressions.
1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12  import os import quandl import pickle import warnings import numpy as np import pandas as pd import seaborn as sns from tqdm.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Comparison Between Exponential Weighted and Rolling Regression</title>
      <link>https://christineeeeee.com/posts/regression_comparison/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 May 2020 21:16:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://christineeeeee.com/posts/regression_comparison/</guid>
      <description>This research discusses two normal prediction ways people are using: exponential weighted regression and rolling regression. By comparing the prediction errors of both ways, we generally get the idea of the difference between these two regressions.
1. Introduction Comparison between two ways of regression  Exponential Weighted Moving Regression: considering all the previous data to do the regression, however, following the intuition that the nearer data have more effects on the future data, the weight of data are different regarding time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Flair - A Pretrained NLP Sentiment Analysis Tool</title>
      <link>https://christineeeeee.com/posts/nlp_sentiment_tool/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 May 2020 09:20:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://christineeeeee.com/posts/nlp_sentiment_tool/</guid>
      <description>NLP(Natural Language Processing) includes sentiment analysis. Trained sentiment analysis includes machine learning, which is of course more accurate. For beginners who just stepped into this field, getting to know some pretrained sentiment analysis tools may also be a good choice. Here, I want to introduce a package I used to analyze sentiment. It&amp;rsquo;s called flair.
Flair&amp;rsquo;s mechanism is simple. It contains a powerful library which allows users to use and combine different word and document embeddings.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Twint - A Twitter Scaping Tool</title>
      <link>https://christineeeeee.com/posts/twint/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 May 2020 17:16:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://christineeeeee.com/posts/twint/</guid>
      <description>Recently I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on a python project about a twitter sentiment trading strategy(which will be introduced in my following posts), which requires a large load of tweets. While collecting data on Twitter, I found out that usual data crawling doesn&amp;rsquo;t work here since there&amp;rsquo;s limitation of Twitter&amp;rsquo;s API which only allows us to scrap at most last 3200 Tweets. This post introduces a really interesting and useful python package I found out which could be used to collect data without authentication, API and limitations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes and Thoughts of Quibi</title>
      <link>https://christineeeeee.com/posts/quibi/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Apr 2020 11:11:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://christineeeeee.com/posts/quibi/</guid>
      <description>1
Like everything in the world, the launch of Quibi was deeply affected by the COVID-19. Maybe in Jeffrey&amp;rsquo;s plan, there would be a huge ceremony to announce the birth of Quibi, however, nowadays, with the process of quarantine, any pre-plan seemed in vain. Boldly but not surprisingly, like he refused to produce the Beta version of this app to let a small portion of potential consumers to test it first with $1 billion funding, Jeffrey Katzenberg, the founder of Quibi, decided to not delay the launch of this app.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Return Predictions From Trade Flow</title>
      <link>https://christineeeeee.com/posts/trade_flow/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Apr 2020 13:24:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://christineeeeee.com/posts/trade_flow/</guid>
      <description>This is a strategy which is based on tick level analysis. The idea is that we use trade flow as our signals of the market to generate profit opportunities.
We define j as our trading threshold. Also, we need to decide proper $\tau$ as the backward trade interval and T as the forward trade interval.
1. Introduction Breif intro of the strategy.
Order Book and Trade Marking In the order book, there&amp;rsquo;re two types of trades: bid and ask.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Duolingo&#39;s English Proficiency Test</title>
      <link>https://christineeeeee.com/posts/duolingo/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Apr 2020 21:16:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://christineeeeee.com/posts/duolingo/</guid>
      <description>1.
As I was looking through Weibo(the most popular social platform in China, like Twitter), I noticed one of my friend&amp;rsquo;s weibo saying that she was pretty upset because her Duolingo English Proficiency Test&amp;rsquo;s result was invalid again. This was her third time taking Duolingo Test and for the first and the second time, the result was cancelled, too.
2.
For international students, taking TOEFL or IELTS test is a necessary step if they want to go abroad to have further study.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quantile Trading</title>
      <link>https://christineeeeee.com/posts/hw4_christine-li/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Apr 2020 12:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://christineeeeee.com/posts/hw4_christine-li/</guid>
      <description>This is a strategy which we trade different securities by ranking their performance and using their quantile as signals.
1. Data preparation Introduction of the packages we used We&amp;rsquo;re using several really important python packages in this strategy:
 Pandas: dataframe manipulation NumPy: support for mathematical functions and computation of arrays and matrics Quandl: source of our future data Statsmodel: statistical analysis Matplotlib: plot tools Seaborn: statistical data visualization Glob: retrieve files matching a specified pattern os: interact with the operating system tqdm: progress bar  1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14  import os import numpy as np import pandas as pd import pickle import quandl import warnings from functools import reduce from tqdm.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>世界上的房思琪们</title>
      <link>https://christineeeeee.com/posts/bombshell/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Apr 2020 17:57:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://christineeeeee.com/posts/bombshell/</guid>
      <description>一点思考。
1
昨晚（趁男朋友睡觉）看完了《爆炸新闻》。片子不怎么样，剧本写得巨烂无比，浪费了塞隆和妮可基德曼这么强的阵容。我想了想给打三星左右，一来在于演员演技好，二来是在当前的语境下，这样一部聚集了强大卡司阵容的片子，还是能够吸引一部分人的关注的。不管导演的目的是什么，这个议题被关注、被讨论，总是好的。
2
中国近几年MeToo运动轰轰烈烈的展开——蒙在“性侵”这个话题上的遮羞布被彻底揭开——在我的印象里始于《房思琪的初恋乐园》的出版以及作者林奕含的自杀。我心理非常脆弱，通常情况下，涉及性侵情节和细节描述的书籍和电影我都是不敢看的。这样的弊端是我因此错过了很多优秀的作品，这方面题材的佼佼者，大名鼎鼎的《熔炉》和《素媛》，我更是听完了情节简介就做了一晚上噩梦。但看完《房思琪的初恋乐园》的作家林奕含的访谈，她的谈吐和经历带给我的共情感，让我觉得自己非看这本书不可。在后来浏览豆瓣上关于这本书的评价时，很多人提到了阅读这本书时难以忍受的痛感。我当年看这本书时，我是没办法提高阅读速度的。看几页，我就得停下来缓一缓。那种生理和心理上的极度不适感，时隔几年，在我回忆起书中的某些情节时，还像当年一样鲜活。林奕含献祭一般，把自己的心血和生命献给了这本书。
当时的我写了一点东西 ，一段是这样的：“让我真正觉得难受的 是作者被诱奸时 才只是十三岁的孩子 我的十三岁稀松平常又无忧无虑 回想起来没有任何一件能让我痛苦得铭记终生的事情 然而对她来讲 这一生 对待自我 对待男性 对待两性间的平等和差异 对待爱情和婚姻 甚至对待生命 所有的认知 都要屈服于年少时可怕经历的阴影”。
回想起来，我的性启蒙，如同绝大多数同龄人，绝不是始于父母的引导。读完《房思琪的初恋乐园》，我觉得后怕。我没有遭受相同的经历并不是因为我被保护得有多好，更主要的原因是，我幸运，我只是个幸存者。
3
《爆炸新闻》里，主角有过一段独白，大体意思是，每次伤害发生的时候，受害者都会问自己：我那天说了什么？我穿了什么？我做了什么事情？我为什么被这样对待，而别人没有？
《房思琪的初恋乐园》里，房思琪整晚整晚地睡不着，只觉得羞耻，觉得是自己做错了什么才让这些发生在自己身上。发生在她身上的性侵贯穿了她的青春期。
我读过一篇报道，是常给《New Yorker》撰稿的青年作家，终于在长大后释怀，在专栏中讲述了自己童年时被性侵的故事。他提到（是的，是“他”。性侵的受害者，从来不仅仅是女性。），他童年时被他的邻居性侵，结束后，邻居让他下周再过来，于是下周，在邻居找他前，他主动去找了邻居。常有人质疑，如果你不是自愿的，你为什么会去主动找施暴者？真正让我难过的事情就是在这里。受害者知道侵害一定会发生，但他不能够控制这件事会不会发生，出于本能的应激机制让他的主动行为给了他一种自己也在somehow掌握主动权的错觉：我不能控制这件事能否发生，那我起码可以控制这件事什么时候发生。
N号房闹得轰轰烈烈，报道里写，犯罪分子就是在利用女孩们的羞耻心，用她们的裸照来威胁她们替他做事。
中国MeToo运动的参与者之一，弦子，曾经在朱军的化妆间被朱军性侵（未得逞）。她也曾陷入迷思，觉得这件事没有被第三者看到，无人为自己作证，同时自己也没有在这件事发生后的第一时间站出来，这样的自己究竟有没有资格在事后站出来挑明真相。最后她还是选择站出来，因为每个人都不是完美受害者。
但什么是所谓的完美受害者呢？受害者这个名词原本就是要表述“一个受到伤害的人”这个既定事实。“受害”才是这件事的重点。但人们的关注点却常常跑偏，落脚在了是否“完美”上。
4
今天看到微博话题，#总裁父亲涉嫌性侵未成年女儿三年#。这个人是烟台一家跨国石油服务集团的副总裁和首席法务官，他的养女只有14岁。养女甚至报了警，可当晚，这人就若无其事毫发无损地回了家。
之前看到农村一小学里的男教师在讲台上当众让自己的学生坐在自己腿上以方便对她进行侵害，每次性侵过后，他都会给她几块钱。
此类报道数不胜数，我以为自己已经有了强心脏，对此类新闻会多一点免疫，但每次看到细节，看到女孩子的哭嚎和鲜血淋漓，还是痛得手脚发软。
像我之前说的，我可以是她们其中的任何一个。我十几岁的时候脑袋里也没有性知识，更不懂得对成年男性怀有警惕心。我们或许对陌生人有戒备，可如今的新闻报道显示，熟人犯案数不胜数，我也曾在手无缚鸡之力的年龄无数次和（认识的）成年男性独处一室，他们若有坏心思，我百分之百可以受伤害。所以说，不是我自我保护意识有多强有多好，只是因为我幸运。
一想到这个，才是真正让人痛。
发生在她们身上的事，完全可以发生在我身上，我认识的任何人身上。
5
这里只谈了性侵的几种而已。婚内性侵呢？有多少人真的明白即便是在婚姻关系内，一方强迫另一方发生性行为，照样也是性侵的一种？我至今还记得那个视频，穿着睡衣逃到公交车上的女子，衣衫不整，被丈夫压制在公交车后排。后来民警做调查，一听说他们是夫妻，便立刻放过了。
世界上有无数个房思琪。被发现的，没被发现的，发声后被忽略的。太痛了。</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spread Trading Strategy</title>
      <link>https://christineeeeee.com/posts/spread_trading/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Mar 2020 22:16:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://christineeeeee.com/posts/spread_trading/</guid>
      <description>This is a spreading strategy which is based on M-day returns of two highly related futures. The idea of this strategy is to hedge the risk of buying and holding one specific future with increasing returns by holding the opposite position of another future.
We define g and j be our trading thresholds in this strategy. Besides, we also have stop-loss threshold s. Our initial capital K is $100MM.
1. Introduction In this section we give brief intro on the strategy we&amp;rsquo;re about to implement.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>5 Ways of Generating Fibonacci Numbers</title>
      <link>https://christineeeeee.com/posts/fib/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Mar 2020 01:24:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://christineeeeee.com/posts/fib/</guid>
      <description>This is just a quick note about 5 ways of generating Fibonacci numbers. Here, I want to create a function whose argument is an int number &amp;ldquo;n&amp;rdquo; (representing which number to return in the Fibonacci sequence). This function will return the Fibonacci number I want. In my definition for this question, I want the Fibonacci sequence to start from 0.
1. Recursion without Cache 1 2 3 4 5  def fib(n): if n &amp;lt;= 2: return n - 1 else: return fib(n - 1) + fib(n - 2)   The time complexity of this function is $O(1.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>