<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Newsletters on Stop this train</title>
    <link>https://christineeeeee.com/newsletter/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Newsletters on Stop this train</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 18 Aug 2020 14:18:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://christineeeeee.com/newsletter/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 08/17/2020 - 08/23/2020</title>
      <link>https://christineeeeee.com/newsletter/newletter_200817-200823/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Aug 2020 14:18:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://christineeeeee.com/newsletter/newletter_200817-200823/</guid>
      <description>Monday Aug.17th, 2020  The Nasdaq advanced 1% to 11129.73, hitting an all-time high. The S&amp;amp;P 500 rose slightly but fell short of a record closing high once again amid declining trading volumes and lingering concerns over a U.S. coronavirus stimulus bill. Bitcoin&amp;rsquo;s price went past $12000 to its highest level. Robinhood announced a $200 million Series G round. The Trump administration approved to open Alaska&amp;rsquo;s Arctic National Wildlife Refuge to drilling for oil and gas.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 08/10/2020 - 08/16/2020</title>
      <link>https://christineeeeee.com/newsletter/newsletter_200809-200816/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Aug 2020 10:29:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://christineeeeee.com/newsletter/newsletter_200809-200816/</guid>
      <description>Monday Aug.10th, 2020  Uber and Lyft ordered by California judge to classify drivers as employees. The injunction is stayed for 10 days, however, giving Uber and Lyft an opportunity to appeal the decision. Uber said it planned to file an immediate emergency appeal to block the ruling from going into effect. Simon Property Group, the states&amp;rsquo; largest mall landlord, reported its $1.1 billion revenue (declined 24%) in Q2 due to the failure of collecting all rents and also the covid-19 closure.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 08/03/2020 - 08/09/2020</title>
      <link>https://christineeeeee.com/newsletter/newsletter_200803-200809/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Aug 2020 10:29:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://christineeeeee.com/newsletter/newsletter_200803-200809/</guid>
      <description>Monday Aug.3rd, 2020  Chinses government and citizens attacked both U.S. government and ByteDance. The Communist Party accused the force sale of &amp;ldquo;hunting and looting&amp;rdquo; of TikTok. Chinese social users accused ByteDance of ceasing to fight with U.S. Government. Google announced to buy 6.6% stake in home security companyADT for $450 million. ADT will assure the installation and maintenance of Google&amp;rsquo;s Nest line of home security devices. Also, Google will promote a trio of new Pixel smartphones.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 07/27/2020 - 08/02/2020</title>
      <link>https://christineeeeee.com/newsletter/newsletter_200727-200802/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jul 2020 10:29:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://christineeeeee.com/newsletter/newsletter_200727-200802/</guid>
      <description>Monday Jul.27th, 2020  Senate Republicans proposed a $1 trillion coronavirus aid package and called this act &amp;ldquo;HEALS Act&amp;rdquo;. The ICE U.S. Dollar Index DXY, 0.07% slipped to a two-year low below 94.00. Google will keep its employees home until at least next July. Biotech firm Moderna got extra $472 million in COVID-19 vaccine funding from the US government. Also, it cooperates with the National Institutes of Health to begin one of the first large study of COVID-19.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 07/20/2020 - 07/26/2020</title>
      <link>https://christineeeeee.com/newsletter/newsletter_200720_200726/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jul 2020 09:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://christineeeeee.com/newsletter/newsletter_200720_200726/</guid>
      <description>Monday Jul.20th, 2020  A Covid-19 vaccine developed by Oxford University and AstraZeneca caused an immune response in a study of roughly 1000 patients (Patients have mild to moderate side effects including fever, headaches and muscle pain). Besides, another study coducted by Chinese Cansino also showed positve antibody responses in a Phase 2 trial. Although it&amp;rsquo;s still early, WHO said the states may have a deal with AstraZeneca and produce 300 million doses this fall if the results are still good.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 07/13/2020 - 07/19/2020</title>
      <link>https://christineeeeee.com/newsletter/newsletter_200713_200719/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jul 2020 13:13:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://christineeeeee.com/newsletter/newsletter_200713_200719/</guid>
      <description>Wednesday Jun.15th, 2020  S&amp;amp;P 500, Dow Jones and Nasdaq were back to positive. Goldman Sachs reported a 150% spike in trading revenues. Many blue check accounts(including Bill Gates, Elon Musk, Barack Obama, Joe Biden etc.) in Twitter were hacked by bitcoin spammers. It took hours to go back to normal. Twitter&amp;rsquo;s stock fell 3%. Walmart requires customers to wear masks. Zoom revealed a $599 work from home package including a tablet, 8 microphones and 3 cameras.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>